independent.com.mt 2019-11-11

# Privacy Policy - The Malta Independent

In this context –

    •  “company” shall mean The Malta Independent and/or its affiliates;

    •  “user” shall mean any person who accesses the TMI website, irrespective of the manner of access and includes users who register an account with TMI website;

    •  “TMI website” shall mean the digital information network operated by or on behalf of the company, irrespective of the manner of access.

This Privacy Policy explains how the company collects, uses, shares or otherwise processes personal information that you provide to us, or that we may otherwise obtain or generate, which relates to you. Please take a moment to review this Privacy Policy and, if you have any questions, feel free to get in touch via one of the methods set out under the header " _Questions and contact information_ " below.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 25 May 2018.

### What personal information do we collect?

When you visit our website, we may collect personal information about you when you provide it to us or interact with us directly. This may include your name and surname, your e-mail address and your mobile phone number.

We gather and generate information about you when you provide it to us or interact with us directly. We may also receive professional information about you from other sources, including publicly available sources. We may combine information that we have about you from various sources, including the information that you have provided to us.

If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason, like marketing, we will ask you directly for your express consent.

### How do I withdraw my consent?

If after you opt in to giving us your personal information, you change your mind, you may withdraw your consent at any time, by contacting us at (00356) 21345888 or mailing us at tmid@independent.com.mt.

### Why do we collect your personal information?

We may use your personal information to:

    •  Allow you to register on our website and leave comments on individual articles;

    •  Apply for subscriptions to our newspaper;

    •  Book advertisements on our newspaper;

    •  Provide you with information, including marketing communications;

    •  Send important notices, such as changes to our terms, conditions and policies;

    •  For internal purposes such as auditing and research; and

    •  To ensure we have up-to-date contact information for you.

We may also be required to process your personal data for the purpose of:

    •  Complying with applicable laws, rules, regulations, guidance and codes;

    •  Complying with demands or requests made by local and foreign regulators, governments, courts and law enforcement authorities, and complying with a court process, or in connection with any litigation.

### Cookies

A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. Cookies are created for each session when you visit our website. None of the information collected by means of cookies is associated with you as an individual. We do not use the cookie technology to capture individual e-mail addresses or any personally identifying information about you. In fact, very little information is automatically gathered and logged.

This website uses 3 types of cookies as follows:

    •  Session cookies - used to track the user session while browsing the website;

    •  Marketing cookies - used for marketing and tracking purposes (e.g. Google & Facebook);

    •  Third party cookies - generated and used by third parties which are integrated on our website (e.g. dealtoday.com.mt & jobsinmalta.com).

Should you wish to reject all or certain cookies used by our website, you may modify your web browser preferences to do so. If however you reject all cookies, your user experience may be affected by this choice and you might be unable to use some of the services available on our website. Moreover, you may set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the opportunity to choose whether or not you wish to accept it. Usually, the information on how to change your options regarding cookies can be obtained by referring to your operating systems manual or to the 'Help' section of your web browser, or by contacting your Internet Service Provider.

### Disclosure to third parties

We may disclose your personal information if we are required by law, regulation, guidance and codes to do so or if you violate our Terms of Use, or in compliance with demands or requests made by local and foreign regulators, governments, courts and law enforcement authorities, and complying with a court process, or in connection with any litigation.

### E-Paper

Our E-Paper is hosted on a third party platform. If you choose to access the E-Paper, you will be taken to a third party website having its own Terms and Conditions and Cookie Policy. We recommend that you read these to understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these third parties.

We make every effort to use only third party providers of good repute and to ensure that they take all necessary measures to protect your data to the best of their abilities, in accordance with best industry practices and according to law.

Once you leave our store's website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website's Terms of Use.

### Security

We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. Our suppliers are carefully selected and required to use appropriate measures to protect the confidentiality and security of your information.

### Your rights as a data subject

You have the right to:

    •  Ask us about the processing of your personal information, including to be provided with a copy of your personal information held by the company;

    •  Request the correction and/or deletion of your personal information, or restrict or object to the processing of your personal information;

    •  Request to obtain and reuse your personal information for your own purposes across different services; and

    •  Complain to a competent supervisory authority, or to a court of law, if your data protection rights are violated or you have suffered as a result of unlawful processing of your personal information.

If you would like access to the information that we hold about you, if any of the information that we hold about you is inaccurate or out of date, or if you wish to restrict or object to us processing it, please let us know by getting in touch via one of the methods set out under the header " _Questions and contact information_ " below.

If you object to our processing of your personal information, we will respect such requests in accordance with our legal obligations. Your objection may mean that we may not be able to perform the actions necessary to achieve the purposes set out above.

We may be required or entitled to retain your information to comply with legal and regulatory obligations and to protect and exercise our legal rights and legitimate interests.

### Recipients and sharing of your personal information

Your personal information will be received by the company's representatives, agents and employees. 

We may also share your personal information with any of the following:

    •  other companies forming part of the company, affiliate companies and companies having the same shareholding as the company or in which it has a controlling interest, for legitimate business purposes;

    •  our agents, suppliers and business partners strictly as required in order to carry out the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy;

    •  our professional advisors and auditors strictly as required for consultation purposes or for compliance with our legal obligations;

    •  regulators, governments and law enforcement authorities as and when this is required under applicable laws and regulations;

    •  courts, tribunals, arbitrators or other competent bodies who may have authority to request such personal information;

    •  other third parties in connection with our selling, merging, buying or reorganising all or any part of our business, or carrying out any similar change of our business (including any potential or actual purchaser of that business or that purchaser's advisors).

### Transfers outside the European Union

We may transfer your personal information outside of Malta. The countries to which your personal information is transferred may not offer an equivalent level of protection for personal information to the laws of Malta. Where appropriate, we will take steps to ensure your information is transferred subject to appropriate safeguards, such as by entering into data transfer agreements. Where we have put data transfer agreements or similar safeguards in place, we may be able to make a copy of this available to you if you contact us via one of the methods set out under the header " _Questions and contact Information_ " below.

Data retention

We have a data retention policy that sets out how long we keep your information. This policy is based on the type of information, the purpose of collection and the system within our digital platforms in which the information is held. As a general rule, we keep your personal information for as long as we need to in order to carry out those purposes for which your data has been collected.

We may be required or entitled to retain your information to comply with legal and regulatory obligations and to protect and exercise our legal rights and legitimate interests.

### Questions and contact information

The Malta Independent is the controller of your personal information. The contact person for data protection related matters is Noel Azzopardi.

_Contact Information_

Should you have any questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy you may contact us through any of the following methods:

By phone: (00356) 21345888

By e-mail: nazzopardi@indepenent.com.mt

By mail: The Managing Director

               Standard Publication Ltd       

               Standard House (Level 2)

               Birkirkara Hill

               St Julian's STJ1149

               Malta
